<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demo | WOW-BLOGGG</title>
    <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/category/demo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://bezura.github.io/en/category/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Demo</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://bezura.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Demo</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/category/demo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino project development</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/arduino/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Arduino is an electronic project development platform that allows you to build devices and automated systems using a microcontroller. If you are interested in electronics and programming, Arduino can be a great choice for your creative and engineering ideas. In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at some key aspects of Arduino project development.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-learn-the-basics-of-arduino&#34;&gt;1. Learn the basics of Arduino.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start developing projects on Arduino, it&amp;rsquo;s important to learn the basics of the platform. Become familiar with Arduino hardware components such as boards, microcontrollers, I/O ports, etc. Also learn the Arduino programming language, which is based on C++. Understanding the basic concepts and functions of Arduino will help you create projects more efficiently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-choose-the-right-arduino-platform&#34;&gt;2. Choose the right Arduino platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many different Arduino platforms on the market, each with different features and characteristics. Choose the Arduino platform that best suits your needs and project requirements. Different platforms may differ in power, size, analog and digital port availability, and other parameters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-select-the-components-you-need&#34;&gt;3. Select the components you need&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your project, you will need various electronic components such as resistors, sensors, displays, motors, etc. Create a list of required components and purchase them. Pay attention to the compatibility of the components with the chosen Arduino platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-start-with-simple-projects&#34;&gt;4. Start with simple projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are new to Arduino development, it is recommended to start with simple projects. For example, LED indicators, buttons, sound signals or motor controls. This will help you learn the basics of Arduino and programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-explore-examples-and-libraries&#34;&gt;5. Explore examples and libraries&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arduino has an extensive library and many example projects that can be used in your development. Explore&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;available examples and libraries to see what features and functions are already implemented and can be used in your projects. This will save you time and improve development efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-keep-experimenting-and-learning&#34;&gt;6. Keep experimenting and learning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arduino offers endless possibilities for creativity and engineering projects. Keep experimenting, create new projects, and deepen your knowledge. Use online resources, forums, and Arduino communities to share experiences and get support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope these tips will help you get started developing Arduino projects. Remember that creativity and persistence play an important role in achieving success. Good luck with your Arduino development!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Share your Arduino projects and experiences in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Disclaimer: Make sure that you follow the appropriate safety rules and guidelines when working with Arduino electricity and components.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/biblic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/biblic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working with Bibliography&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Creating a reliable and well-organized bibliography is an integral part of successful scholarly work. It allows readers to verify your sources and protects you from accusations of plagiarism. In this post, we will explore some important aspects of working with a bibliography and provide you with useful tips.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-choose-the-correct-citation-style&#34;&gt;1. Choose the correct citation style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous citation styles such as APA, MLA, Chicago, and others. It is important to choose the one that aligns with the requirements of your field of study or the academic journal you plan to publish in. Each style has its own specifications regarding citation format and formatting of the reference list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-use-bibliography-management-software&#34;&gt;2. Use bibliography management software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various programs and online services exist for managing bibliographic data, such as Zotero, Mendeley, EndNote, and others. They allow you to organize and store citations and complete bibliographic information, as well as automatically generate reference lists in the required style. Utilizing a bibliography management tool simplifies the citation process and minimizes the risk of errors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-maintain-a-bibliographic-record-for-each-source&#34;&gt;3. Maintain a bibliographic record for each source&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When working with literature, maintain a meticulous bibliographic record for each source you use. The record should contain all necessary details, such as authors, article or book title, year of publication, publisher, etc. This will help you easily reference sources in your text and create accurate citations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-check-for-accuracy-and-completeness&#34;&gt;4. Check for accuracy and completeness&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before presenting your work, it is important to check the accuracy and completeness of your bibliography. Ensure that all sources are properly formatted according to the chosen citation style. Also, verify that you haven&amp;rsquo;t missed any sources used and that all in-text citations have corresponding entries in the reference list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-be-consistent&#34;&gt;5. Be consistent&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consistency in formatting your bibliography is crucial. Follow the chosen citation style consistently throughout your work. Check that you use the same formats for different types of sources (books&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;, journal articles, web pages, etc.). This helps create a professional and high-quality impression of your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope these tips assist you in working with your bibliography. A clear and properly formatted bibliography enhances the quality of your scholarly work and makes it more persuasive to readers and reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Share your thoughts and experiences with bibliography management in the comments below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Make sure to check the requirements of your educational institution or academic journal for specific bibliography formatting rules. Citation styles and requirements may vary.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/scientific_programming_languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:01:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/scientific_programming_languages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;scientific-programming-languages&#34;&gt;Scientific programming languages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a field that uses computer languages and technologies to solve scientific problems such as data analysis, physical process modeling, machine learning, and others. There are many programming languages that are suitable for scientific purposes, but some are more popular and common than others. In this post, I will discuss three such languages: Python, R, and Julia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is a high-level interpreted programming language with dynamic typing and many libraries for scientific computing. Python is easy to learn and use, has a clean and clear syntax, supports multi-paradigm programming (object-oriented, functional, procedural, etc.) and has a large community of developers and users. Some of the best known libraries for scientific programming in Python include NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn and TensorFlow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;r&#34;&gt;R&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R is a programming language and environment for statistical analysis and data visualization. R is designed specifically for working with data and has many built-in functions and packages for it. R also supports various types of charts and graphs that can be easily created and customized. R is an interpreted language with dynamic typing and a functional programming paradigm. Popular packages for scientific R programming include Tidyverse, ggplot2, Shiny and R Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;julia&#34;&gt;Julia&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julia is a relatively new programming language, designed to combine the speed of execution of low-level languages (like C or Fortran) with the expressiveness and convenience of high-level languages (like Python or R). Julia compiles to machine code before execution and has a powerful multiple dispatch system, which allows to define behavior of functions depending on types and number of arguments. Julia also supports metaprogramming, parallel and distributed computing, interoperability with other languages and a rich set of libraries for scientific programming. These include Plots, DataFrames, Flux and DifferentialEquations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming languages are tools that help scientists and engineers solve complex problems in various fields of knowledge. The choice of language depends on the specific task at hand.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Report _3_.</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/my_last_week-_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/my_last_week-_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-i-spent-the-past-week&#34;&gt;How I spent the past week&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi friends, I want to tell you how I spent my week in my hometown. It was wonderful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Friday I visited my family and we had a long chat over dinner. They were very happy to see me and gave me a warm welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, I met up with my friends from school. We gathered at our favorite cafe and talked over a cup of coffee. We exchanged our experiences, laughed at old jokes, and reminisced about our adventures and dreams. We also visited our school and our classroom teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, I spent the day outdoors with my family. We went for a picnic by the river. The weather was beautiful: sunny, warm and refreshing. We enjoyed the beauty of nature, rode our bikes, played ball, fished, and swam in the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, I started getting ready to leave. I packed my things, gave my family souvenirs from the city where I study, and thanked them for all they do for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am so glad I was able to visit my hometown and spend time with my loved ones. It was one of the most memorable and enjoyable weeks of my life!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown markup language</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; is a text markup language created by writer and blogger John Gruber. It&amp;rsquo;s designed to create beautifully formatted text in regular TXT files. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a cumbersome word processor like Word or Pages to create documents with bold or italic type, quotations, links, and even tables. All you need to do is memorize the simple rules of Markdown and you can even write in Notepad. A dedicated Markdown editor is a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a markup language used by bloggers, writers, editors and journalists all over the world. Everyone involved in those professions will find it useful to know about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#*Where you can use Markdown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; editor with a file panel (like Atom or iA Writer) is a pretty decent alternative to Evernote and OneNote. We&amp;rsquo;ve written before about why Markdown is good for organizing your note base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;drafts-for-blogging&#34;&gt;Drafts for Blogging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This markup language is compatible with a bunch of online editors and blogging platforms. You can write a draft for your blog in Markdown and then publish it in seconds - all the links, headings, and formatting will look just as you intended. It&amp;rsquo;s not like copying from Word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;task-lists&#34;&gt;Task Lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown editors make it very easy to create shopping lists, to-do lists, and work task lists. Some geeks use a regular todo.txt text file as an alternative to fancy Wunderlist and Todoist. You can learn how to do this at Todo.txt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;messengers&#34;&gt;Messengers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even some messengers support Markdown. In Telegram, for example, you can use Markdown to apply bold or italic highlighting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-advantages-of-markdown&#34;&gt;The advantages of Markdown&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;versatility&#34;&gt;Versatility&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Documents written using the Markdown syntax are plain TXT text files. They can be opened on any platform and in any editor. This makes them different from text processor files. Have you ever tried opening an Apple Pages document in Word?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;simplicity&#34;&gt;Simplicity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is so simple that even people who haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of Latex and HTML can learn it in 10 minutes. Grids for subheadings, asterisks for highlighting, dashes for lists. It couldn&amp;rsquo;t be easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-wide-range-of-tools&#34;&gt;A wide range of tools&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many, many editors for Markdown documents. There are online, mobile, and desktop tools. There is the monster Atom, the beautiful and minimalistic ghostwriter and iA Writer, Vim for geeks and Ulysses for professional writers. Take your pick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;convertibility&#34;&gt;Convertibility.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown documents can be easily exported in any format such as PDF, DOC and ODT. Their formatting remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Недельный отчёт(УЖЕ ВТОРОЙ!!!).</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/my_last_week-_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/my_last_week-_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;beginning-at&#34;&gt;Beginning at&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, yes&amp;hellip; Unexpectedly, even for me, that the second such post. But, unfortunately or fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s not my whims (laba, it&amp;rsquo;s all her&amp;hellip;). What about the week, everything is great, summer is coming, the weather is super) I wish everyone happiness!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control. Git.</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/git_versions_control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/git_versions_control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;version-control-systemsgeneral-concepts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control Systems.General Concepts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control Systems (VCS)&lt;/strong&gt; are used when several people work on a project. Usually the main project tree is stored in a local or remote repository, to which access is set up for project members. When changes are made to the project content, version control systems allow you to commit changes, merge changes made by different project members, and revert to any earlier version of the project if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classic version control systems use a centralized model, which implies a single repository for storing files. Most version control functions are performed by a special server. A project participant (user) obtains the necessary version of the files before starting to work, and after making changes, the user places the new version into the repository, so that previous versions are not deleted from the central repository and can be returned to at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems support the ability to track and resolve conflicts that may arise when several people work on the same file. You can merge changes made by different participants (automatically or manually), manually select the correct version, discard changes at all or lock files for modification. Depending on the settings, locking prevents other users from getting a working copy or prevents modification of the working copy by the OS file system, thereby ensuring that the version of the file is not changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems can also provide additional, more flexible functionality. For example, they can support multiple versions of the same file, keeping an overall history of changes up to the branching point and each branch&amp;rsquo;s own change history. In addition, information is usually available about which participant made which changes, when, and what changes. Usually, this kind of information is stored in a change log, access to which can be restricted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast to classical VCSs, in distributed version control systems a central repository is optional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the classical VCSs the most famous are CVS, Subversion, and among the distributed ones - Git, Bazaar, Mercurial, etc. The principles of their work are similar, the main difference is the syntax of the commands used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-git-version-control-system&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Git version control system&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Git version control system&lt;/strong&gt; is a collection of command-line programs. These can be accessed from the terminal by entering the git command with various options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Git is a distributed version control system, you can back up your local repository by simply copying or archiving it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-git-commands&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basic git commands&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used git commands are given in the table below&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Команда Описание















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.003_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_688_0df2a83cd9f1cb3ce58ad42648ff527b.webp 400w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.003_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_688_b3dbd59a68ead789d8cba558f9763a77.webp 760w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.003_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_688_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://bezura.github.io/en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.003_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_688_0df2a83cd9f1cb3ce58ad42648ff527b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;396&#34;
               height=&#34;4&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git init creating the main repository tree&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git pull to retrieve updates (changes) to the current tree from the&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;central repository&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git push push any changes you have made to the local&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;to the central repository&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git status to browse the list of changed files in the current&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;directory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git diff to review the current changes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git add . add all modified and/or created files and/or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;directories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git add specific modified and/or created file names and/or directories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git rm to remove the file and/or directory from the repository index (which keeps the file and/or directory in the local directory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git commit to save any changes you&amp;rsquo;ve added and any changes you&amp;rsquo;ve changed -am &amp;lsquo;commit file description&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Command Description















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.006_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_714_ed37140d8cba3750b15ff95b50ae1446.webp 400w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.006_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_714_102a0a22eb70a423e8669077e77aa66a.webp 760w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.006_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_714_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://bezura.github.io/en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.006_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_714_ed37140d8cba3750b15ff95b50ae1446.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;396&#34;
               height=&#34;4&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git checkout create a new branch based on the current branch -b branch name_name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git checkout switch to some branch (switching to a branch name that isn&amp;rsquo;t already in the local repository will&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;branch that isn&amp;rsquo;t yet in the local repository is created and linked to a remote branch)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git push to send branch changes to the central origin repository&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;branch name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git merge branch into current tree &amp;ndash;no-ff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;branch name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git branch -D remove a local branch that has already been merged into the main branch, branch name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git branch -D forcibly deletes a local branch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;branch name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git push branch removal from the central repository&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;origin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:name_branches















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.005_hude4d16939682ab9b348385df5566ab82_642_4a29fc02579d71b47b5ad7d35b33899d.webp 400w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.005_hude4d16939682ab9b348385df5566ab82_642_0e7959a606a4daf3f753e4a72f4217bf.webp 760w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.005_hude4d16939682ab9b348385df5566ab82_642_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://bezura.github.io/en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.005_hude4d16939682ab9b348385df5566ab82_642_4a29fc02579d71b47b5ad7d35b33899d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;395&#34;
               height=&#34;7&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;standard-procedures-for-working-with-a-central-repository&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standard procedures for working with a central repository&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user begins by checking and getting changes from the central repository (no changes should have been made to the local tree before this procedure began):















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.004_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_808_bbb65bbe23e1d1f034f16d7b1c0f0bcc.webp 400w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.004_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_808_725adf504f8973401ca256b0b151daa5.webp 760w,
               /en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.004_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_808_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://bezura.github.io/en/post/git_versions_control/Aspose.Words.d8d007bc-3873-4168-a695-b631a7f23e98.004_hu007c3583c09fc875f62b053086d99185_808_bbb65bbe23e1d1f034f16d7b1c0f0bcc.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;396&#34;
               height=&#34;6&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git checkout master&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git pull&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git checkout -b branch name_name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can then make changes to the local tree and/or branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are done making changes to files and/or directories in your project, you should place them in the central repository. To do this, you need to check which files have changed so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git status&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and if necessary, remove unnecessary files you do not want to upload to the central repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, it is useful to review the changes against the clean commit rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git diff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there are files that should be kept out of the commit, you can use the add and/or remove commands with the appropriate options to keep the changes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git add file names git rm file names&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to keep all changes in the current directory, use: git add .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then save the changes, explaining what was done:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git commit -am &amp;ldquo;Some commit message&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and push it to the central repository:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git push origin branch_name&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;git push&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Report.</title>
      <link>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/my_last_week_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://bezura.github.io/en/post/my_last_week_1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;libr&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s1&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;beginning&#34;&gt;Beginning&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week went pretty normally. I did all my homework on time this week, as usual. Nothing more to say&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
